elagaan.com 2010-01-03

# Privacy Policy | eLagaan

At eLagaan, we place the highest importance on respecting and protecting the privacy of our customers. Our relationship with you is our most important asset. We want you to feel comfortable and confident when using our products and services and with entrusting your personal and tax return information to us.

Our company's resources and entire staff are fully committed to safeguarding your personal data (including email address) by ensuring that the highest security and other precautionary measures are in place to protect your non-public information. That is why we do not share your information (including email address) with third parties, affiliates, or partners in ways other than disclosed in this privacy statement. We only collect, store and use your personal information (including email address) for defined purposes. The purposes include fulfilling orders, supplying service and support, and notifying you of new/enhanced products and services.

At any time, you may contact us to request what information you have given us and request correction or deletion. Our goal is to ensure the highest levels of security and confidentiality.

**Policy Scope**  
This statement applies to the eLagaan web sites and services that display or link to this statement.

**Information Collection**  
eLagaan will only collect, store, use, and share your personal information (including email address) as it is defined by eLagaan's privacy statement and as regulated by government laws. Information collected on the eLagaan website is stored by eLagaan and, unless it is otherwise stated, is only used to complete orders, supply service and support, as well as notify you when new/enhanced products and services become available. We do not disclose your information (including email address) to third parties except as stated in this privacy statement. We do not supplement your personally identifiable customer information (including email address) with information from other companies.

In order to use our services, a user may complete the registration form. During registration a user is required to give contact information (such as name and e-mail address). We use this information to contact you about services on our site, to send a confirmation e-mail, or if we have any trouble processing your order.

If you decide to upgrade your membership to paid services, we request additional information. On the payment information page, we collect financial information such as credit card number and expiration date. This information is used for billing purposes and to fill your order. If we have trouble processing an order, the contact information collected is used to contact you.

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. eLagaan stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program. Your friend may contact us at referrals AT eLagaan DOT com to request that we remove this information from our database.

**Information Use**  
We do not sell or rent your personal or tax return information to anyone. We do not share your personal or tax return information with anyone outside of eLagaan for their promotional or marketing use. We do not share your tax return information inside of eLagaan for promotional or marketing use.

eLagaan uses your personal information to manage your account, to contact you and to operate, improve, and deliver our products and services, including Web sites. We use your personal information to provide you with information and services you request, to tell you about eLagaan products and services, and to give you a customized, interactive experience as you use our products. We use your personal information to charge you for the products and services you purchase. We use the contact information you provide to communicate with you. We use your tax return information to prepare and file your return, and provide related assistance and services.

We use responses to surveys and polls to improve our products and services. We summarize information about your usage and combine it with that of others to learn about the use of eLagaan products to help us develop new products and services. This information is collected in such a way that it can not be used to identify an individual.

We retain copies of your completed and filed tax returns in accordance with eLagaan’s Records and Information Management Policy. This information may also be used to perform analysis relating to your claims under our guarantees, or to provide you with a copy of your returns for your convenience.

We may use service companies on our behalf to perform services for you but these companies are not allowed to use your information for their own purposes.

We may access and/or disclose your information if it is necessary to comply with the law or legal process, to protect or defend eLagaan, or act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of eLagaan services or members of the public. For example, we may be required to cooperate with regulators or law enforcement action such as a court order, subpoena or search warrant.

**Information Security**  
eLagaan works to protect your personal information and tax return information from loss, misuse or unauthorized alteration by using industry-recognized security safeguards, coupled with carefully developed security procedures and practices. We use both internal and external resources to review our security procedures. Whenever we prompt you to transmit sensitive information, such as tax return or credit card information, we support the encryption of your information as it is transmitted to us. Our employees are trained and required to safeguard your information.

eLagaan follows stringent security guidelines to protect the security and privacy of your tax return information. Electronically filed tax returns are encrypted during transmission to us. 

**What you can do to protect your personal information**  
You can take steps in your use of the Internet and online services that will help protect your personal information.

  * Use a firewall to prevent unauthorized access to your computer.
  * Use a virus-checking program and keep it up to date.
  * Keep your operating system and programs up-to-date.
  * If you share a computer with others, close all active programs and log-out before leaving the computer.
  * If you use file-sharing programs, be sure to restrict all other folders or directories to "no share".
  * Choose a user id that is not the same as a government issued identifier or your birthday or some other date or word that is either easily guessed or could cause harm if someone else learned it.
  * Choose a strong password using a combination of letters, numbers and special characters that are meaningful to you and yet not easily guessed by someone else. Keep your password private.
  * Do not trust email requests for personal information. On Web sites, look for the lock symbol which signifies a secure site before supplying personal information. If in doubt, ask.
  * When using open Internet chat and forum services, do not supply personal or financial information. When using tax advice chat and similar services, do not supply more information than necessary to define your problem.
  * Read privacy statements to learn how your information will be collected and used.

See <http://www.staysafeonline.info/basics/consumers.html> for more information.

**Collection and use of Children’s Personal Information**

eLagaan’s services are intended to be used by adults. eLagaan may collect personal information about children as part of the tax return preparation process. The use of tax return information is restricted and any information contained within the return can only be disclosed or used in accordance with applicable laws: to prepare, assist in preparing, or obtain or provide services in connection with preparing your tax return; or to provide you with the products and services you specifically request or consent to.

**Internet technologies**  
We use a variety of technologies on our Web site. Among these are cookies, which are pieces of information that our Web sites provide to your browser. Cookies also allow us to customize your visit to our Web site by recognizing you, for example, when you return to the site. Cookies allow us to track overall site usage and determine areas users prefer. You can choose to decline cookies while at our Web site, however, this may limit your ability to access certain areas of the Web site. Most browsers accept and maintain cookies by default. Check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preference. 

We may access and set cookies using Web beacons, also known as single-pixel GIFs which are invisible graphical images. These Web beacons tell us useful information regarding our site such as which pages web visitors view.

When we track activity on this or other eLagaan Web sites, we collect information such as your IP address, browser type and version, and pages you view. We also keep track of how you get to our sites and any links you click on to leave our sites. We do not track URLs that you type into your browser, nor do we track you across the Internet once you leave our sites. We use your Web site activity to assist you by reducing the need to re-enter your data and to help us resolve technical support issues. We may also use this information to offer you a personalized Web experience, and to tailor our offerings to you. Remember, you control whether you receive eLagaan marketing materials.

To assist us in collecting site usage data, we use service providers to place web beacons on specific pages of our site and pass back usage information about that page via the use of cookies to these service providers. Personally identifiable information is not sent to eLagaan or our service providers through the use of these cookies or web beacons and all web navigation data is used only in the aggregate to improve our product and site performance.

We use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know the number of emails that have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers' personally identifiable information. If you would like to opt-out of these emails, please visit "My account” section.

Advertising networks that serve ads on our Web site may assign a different cookie to you. The information collected is anonymous and is not linked to your personal information. These cookies may be used to select which ads you see and determine the effectiveness of this advertising. You may choose to decline cookies from third-party ad servers, which eLagaan does not control. Any information that these third parties collect via cookies and action tags is completely anonymous. If you would like more information about this practice and your choices, click here (<http://www.advertising.com/Privacy.html>) and here (<http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp>). We do not share, rent or sell any personally identifiable information (including email address) to these companies.

On occasion, we will enter into a written contract with third party intermediary companies to help us to complete a business process, service, or function on our behalf. Without limitation, third party intermediaries may specialize in providing services such as: consulting or contracted development and maintenance, temporary workers, data processing, as well as direct and network marketing. These third party intermediaries may not use or retain personally identifiable information (including email address) for any secondary purpose. Additionally, they may not divulge, rent or sell any information (including email address) that may be gained through their relationship with eLagaan.

eLagaan may also enter into marketing alliances and joint marketing relationships. eLagaan's relationship with these companies shall not represent our endorsement for the products or services these companies offer; and, are only being made available within eLagaan.com to serve as added conveniences for our site's visitors. Unless you have supplied your consent, we do not share your name and other personally identifiable information (including email address); and, we shall never sell or rent any information that identifies you personally or individually. Otherwise, for a third party intermediary to obtain your contact information or personal data, you, yourself, will need to supply them with your information or become their direct customer. If you consent to share your personal information with a 3rd party through eLagaan.com, you may unsubscribe by contacting us.

Written agreements are established between eLagaan and all third party intermediaries, as well as joint marketing and alliance companies. Each agreement strictly limits the use of your personally identifiable information to the scope of the contract. Contractual agreements, such as these, also stipulate safeguard, handling, and other precautionary care procedures, which are required to be taken. The contractual agreements we have in place and/or establish also govern confidentiality rights by limiting the information that we can share to include only aggregated statistical data.

Additionally, we have business partners that provide services, some of which are co-branded. Partner services and sites are clearly identified. When you request any of these products or services, you are permitting us to provide your personal information to the partner to fulfill your request.

Occasionally, eLagaan products are promoted on the Web sites of another organization. In some instances when you access our products through the Web site of that other organization, we may provide your personal information back to that specific organization. When we do so, we will tell you at the time we collect your personal information and we will provide you a link to the organization's Privacy Policy.

We may use sources outside of eLagaan to supplement the personal information you give us. For example, we may validate your address using other sources or we may provide you with demographic, household or non-public personal information. We use this data to help us maintain accuracy and provide you with better products and services.

Lamingo and its subsidiaries may exchange personal information, which may include exchange across country borders, about your transactions to fulfill your requests. We may also provide you information about products or services we believe you may be interested in unless you have asked us not to contact you. We offer you the opportunity to review privacy practices at our subsidiaries' Web sites.

**Links to Other Web Sites**  
eLagaan may contain links to third-party Web sites. Each of these links shall be clearly identified. eLagaan does not direct or oversee the policies, procedures, or other practices for companies other than eLagaan. eLagaan does not endorse the products and services that are offered by third party companies. The presence of third party links within eLagaan.com are for convenience purposes only and should not be considered as representing an endorsement by us. Some of these third party sites may collect information about you or request sensitive, personal information from you. If accessing a third party site via a link, which originated from eLagaan.com you will be subject to the policies and procedures that have been established by the third party. We encourage you to review their privacy policies to learn more about what information is collected, how it is used, and how it is stored.

eLagaan may provide third parties with links to eLagaan.com. Once you have been redirected to a eLagaan.com web page, the terms and conditions of our site shall apply.

**Preferences**  
If you supply us with your postal or email address, you may periodically receive mailings from us containing information on new products, services, or upcoming events. You may choose to be removed from our mailing list by contacting us using one of the methods listed at the bottom of this page (email, phone or mail). If your personally identifiable information changes (such as pin code, phone, email or postal address), we provide a way to correct, and update your personally identifiable information. This can be done by accessing your account online at our site and visiting "My Account" section for the required changes.

If you do not want to receive promotional e-mail from us in the future, please let us know by sending an email or writing to us at the details listed at the bottom of this page and telling us that you do not want to receive e-mail from our company. Please make sure you supply the same e-mail address to us that you are receiving the e-mail from. In some cases, e-mail addresses are being forwarded by your ISP to another e-mail address. We must have the one that is listed in the e-mail you receive from us. In addition, users may unsubscribe by replying to the opt-out instructions at the bottom of each email they receive.

If you supply us with your postal address online you may receive periodic mailings from us with information on new products and services or upcoming events. If you do not wish to receive such mailings, please let us know by sending an email or writing to us at the details listed at the bottom of this page. When requesting to be removed from our mailing list, please provide us with your exact name and address. Alternatively, you may do so by accessing your account online at our site and visiting "My Account" section for the required changes.

Persons who supply us with their telephone numbers on-line may receive telephone contact from us with information regarding orders they have placed on-line. They also may receive telephone contact from us with information regarding new products and services or upcoming events. If you do not wish to receive such telephone calls, please let us know by sending an email or writing to us at the details listed at the bottom of this page. Please provide us with your correct phone number. Alternatively, you may do so by accessing your account online at our site and visiting "My Account" section for the required changes.

**Security Measures**

Our primary concern is that your personal information is private and secure. At eLagaan we use the industry-standard Secure Socket Layers (SSL) protocol which provides data encryption, message integrity, and server authentication when your data is sent to us. When you see a small lock in the bottom right or left corner of your browser window, you know your data is being encrypted for transmission.

All information you enter while using eLagaan is used strictly by us to provide the services requested by our customers. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect your personal information. All data is stored on our servers and is backed up to prevent the loss of data. eLagaan will not sell or rent your name or other personal information (including email address) to any third party in ways other than disclosed in this privacy statement. Personally identifiable information (including email address) is only shared with third party intermediaries providing they have been contracted to act on our behalf or to carry out a specific function. Under these circumstances, third party intermediaries may not sell or transfer this information (including email address) nor may they use information for any secondary purpose.

**Notices and Service Alerts**  
Although we respect and honor your privacy preferences, eLagaan shall maintain and reserve the right to contact you (via email, phone, fax, mail, or otherwise) when it deems appropriate, such as for non-marketing purposes (such as bug alerts, security breaches, and/or changes that may impact your ability to use our products and services). In certain circumstances, we may use our website, newspapers, or other public means to post a notice.

**Service, Support and Suggestions**  
eLagaan offers technical support and customer service on the our product line to our customers. You may choose to submit a question through the service and support section of the eLagaan.com web site or contact our support staff directly. The information submitted via the service and support section (including email address) is not stored or shared with third parties, affiliates, alliance or joint marketing companies, or any other third party intermediaries. It is used to research and address your question, problem, or request for more information. eLagaan retains the right to respond when contact is in direct relationship to your inquiry, request, suggestion, or it becomes necessary when fulfilling an order.

If you make a suggestion using the service and support section of our web site, the suggestion alone may be stored, but no personal data (including email address) will be stored with the suggestion. eLagaan does retain the right to use your suggestions and product enhancement ideas to improve the our web sites and product line without obligation to you.

**General Disclosure of Aggregated Information**  
eLagaan may disclose aggregate information to the tax authorities or other parties, however, may not represent any information, which may be used to identify you personally or individually (including email address) without your expressed consent. Examples may include, but are not limited to: the total number of users served by a eLagaan product/service, general age group ratios, and other statistical data relating to tax preparation and electronic filing service.

**Changes to our Privacy Policy**  
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

If, however, we are going to use users' personally identifiable information (including email address) in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify users by posting a prominent notice on our Web site for 4 weeks.

If we merge with, or are acquired by another company, the resulting combined company will use the Personal Information you have provided as described in this policy. If we cease operation, your Personal Information may be transferred to and used by another company that offers similar or related products or services. You will be notified via prominent notice on our Web site for 30 days of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information. You will also have the opportunity to ask not to receive promotional materials following any change of control.

**Communication with us about Privacy**  
If you have privacy-related questions that are not addressed here, please contact our Privacy Team at privacy AT eLagaan DOT com 

For any other queries you may contact us at support AT eLagaan DOT com

**Disclaimer**  
Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our Web site.

Bookmark/Search this post with:
